

Sachin Dutta

Senior Executive: Fulfillment in Ofcommerce Function

≥ sachindutta11@gmail.com

9779633095

in linkedin.com/in/sachin-dutta-b23724178

SUMMARY

A highly motivated and enthusiastic professional with approx. 2 years of progressive experience in Operations and Logistics with good Vendor Base connection across India. Possesses a strong work ethic and desire to further develop knowledge and Skills. Capable of managing multiple projects at the same time with competing deadlines and committed to delivering promised results.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Vendor Development
- Cost Analysis
- Customer Relation Management
- > Fleet Management
- Business Analysis

- Project Management
- Optimization
- Process Improvement
- People Management

EXPERIENCE

OfBusiness Tech Pvt. Ltd Dec 2021- Present

- 1. Works for Steel Team in the OfCommerce Fulfillment department.
- 2. Look at the dispatches from SAIL Bhilai, Durgapur, Burnpur, and JSPL Raigarh, Angul
- 3. Planning and Placing trailers in SAIL and JSPL
- 4. Coordinate with Transporters to ensure that the fleet is available to place on time. This involves Price Negotiation.
- 5. Create and maintain documentation that involves generating Invoices and E-way bills
- 6. Analyzing and initiating escalations in the event of lack of material availability and transport-related issues during transit.

CPMC Relocation and Logistics Pvt. Ltd Aug 2020 - Dec 2021

- 1. Expertly support and managed day to day transportation operations by continuously analyzing.
- 2. Executed the delivery through cross functional point of contact.
- 3. Consistently employed negotiation skills to secure the most cost-effective delivery solutions for the company
- 4. Successfully managed and executed vendor development.
- 5. Handled Customer Relation and Effectively Improved the process for better Operation.
- 6. Optimizing the stock/Inventory to reduce the overall cost.
- 7. Trained 3 new employees on the current work flow and also provided Excel training sessions.

PGDM Corporate Internship Thomas Cook April 2019 - Aug 2019

- Managed Customer Relation and Project Execution for the following Projects:
 - > Asian Paint Ltd. Classic Premium Club members to Munich
 - Asian Paints ICC World Cup tour
 - > Asian Paints Super Premium Member organized trips to Kenya and Zambia
- Worked as an integral part of the operations department wherein I learned the process through careful observation and implementation of the same.
- 3. Worked closely with the Visa department for the verification of the documents and on boarding of the passengers

Industrial Internship Sonalika 2017

- 1. 4 months Industrial Internship in logistic department from International Tractors Ltd. Hoshiarpur Punjab.
 - Worked with management team to codify best practices within the logistics group.
 - > Incharge of Inventory Management Process to provide recommendations for better operations.
 - > Develops PowerPoint presentations and other graphic presentations to communicate progress and provide updates.

Summer Internship Sonalika 2014

- 1. Summer Internship from International Tractors Ltd. Hoshiarpur Punjab.
 - Worked diligently with the team to ensure timely delivery of product and services
 - Assisted the manager in order to increase efficiency and lower cost while maintaining high level of customer service

PROJECTS

NGO PROJECT 2018

- 1. Completed 15 days NGO project from "Ekam Foundation, Mumbai".
- 2. The major task was:
- > Conducted awareness drive among students on water harvesting and clean drinking water.
- Assisted Guide in preparing for the Classroom sessions

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Diploma in Management (PGDM) Jun 2018 - Jun 2020

ITM Business School, Kharghar

Completed Management in Supply Chain Management & Operations (SCM & OPS) with 67%

Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech) 2013 - 2017

CGC College of Engineering, Landran, Mohali

Completed B. Tech in Mechanical Engineering with 65%

DAV Centenary Public School (CBSE), Una 2012 – 2013

Completed Higher Secondary Certificate (HSC) with 58%

DAV Centenary Public School (CBSE), Una 2010 - 2011

Completed Secondary School Certificate (SSC) with 76%

LANGUAGES

English Punjabi Punjabi

CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES & ACHIEVEMENTS

- > Played State Level Football Tournament
- ➤ Winner of MHRA State Level Football Tournament
- > Represented Himachal Pradesh in National Level U-19 Football Tournament V.C. Roy Trophy in Kolkata
- > Participated in various State Level Football Tournament at School Levels and Open Levels
- ➤ Winner of Melange held in ITM Business School

HOBBIES

- Playing Football
- Listening Music